

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Project and Delivery management experience of 9 years with Fortune 500 clients



Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MTech [Communications

Notice Period: 3 Months

Engineering and IT]

 $\hbox{\it Current Designation: } \textbf{Project Manager}$

Current Company: Capgemini
Current Location: Mumbai

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Navi Mumbai, Dubai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Program Management, Delivery Management, Change Management, JIRA, PMP, Prince 2, Agile Project Management, Scrum Master, Project Management, Troject Management, Software Project Management, SDLC, Risk Management, Agile, Waterfall, PMI, Client Management

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section | Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Possess an overall experience of 9 years in IT Project, Program, and Delivery management Certifications: Prince2, ITIL v3 certified, Scrum Master certified, SAFe 5 Agilist and Lean Six Sigma Black belt certified, Training attended for PMP and the exam is scheduled in Feb 2021

Proven track record of providing leadership and coordinating with multi-functional teams: software developers, testers, business analyst, product team, audit, and CXO stakeholders with team sizes ranging from 22 to 40 Strong technical understanding of software development aspects: Software Development Lifecycle [SDLC] Managed large and complex projects, identified/mitigated potential risks, developed requirements, change management, tracked schedules, and cost performance while ensuring project activities are aligned with the business objectives Excellent communicator and capable of negotiating mutually acceptable solutions

Work Experience

- Capgemini as Project Manager Mar 2019 to Till Date
- Represented as the face for Capgemini for the projects handled and a team of 30
- Onshore exposure with projects across Germany, France, UK and Spain with primary location at the client site
- Responsible for commercial and contract management, resource management, and project financials
- Guide team towards client deliverables and play a keyrole in technical issue resolution
- Manage contracts with vendors and suppliers by assigning tasks and communicating expected deliverables
- Responsible for conducting periodic status meetings and steering committee with internal and client stakeholders
- Scaled Agile [SAFe] was used for project which involved PI planning, daily standups, scrum of scrums, retrospective, and regular interactions with the product owner to help with user stories
- Creating and managing the project documents: Project plan, SOW, Change Issue and Risk log, dashboard
- Received appreciation from the client for suggesting additional features into their product which would enable a better user experience and drive business growth
- Played a key role in creating estimates for creating the project schedule
- Responsible for Risk management and mitigation
- Created a guideline for opensource software compatibility and license evaluation by working with Group Delivery
- Responsible for performing Cybersecurity and Data privacy assessment
- Projects handled were for the financial services sector with implementation for Blockchain products

Yapsody as Project Manager Jun 2018 to Mar 2019

- Articulated project goals, scope, translated business needs into technical requirements, prepared detailed work breakdown structures, and instilled shared accountability for achieving milestones
- Accountable for complete end-to-end delivery of Software development projects which involved working through all phases i.e. initiating, planning, execution, monitoring & control, and closure
- Responsible for conducting all the scrum ceremonies and maintaining project documents
- Control and drive the Program/Project change management and risk management
- · Confluct daily and weekly undate meetings with the internal stakeholders and the clients

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

- Conduct daily and weekly update meetings with the internal stakeholders and the cherts
- Responsible for strategic planning and selections of the projects
- Projects: Cryptocurrency with its own wallet [Yapcoins], enterprise-grade online ticketing system [Web and mobile OS], creating white-label applications for some of the biggest hotel chains in the UK, Europe, Canada, and the US
- Kraftiny as Project Manager Nov 2015 to Jun 2018

Responsible for handling multiple software projects and managing a team with a total headcount of 32 Defined project scopes and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility Responsible for scrum planning, daily standup, review, demo, retrospective and information radiators Maintaining and responsible for kick-off, project charter, stakeholder management, quality management, technical workshops, decision making, vendor management, documentation and risk management Responsible for weekly meetings (Internal, Customer, Stakeholders) to track and update the progress of deliverables Projects: Learning management system, Payment gateway integration, Machine learning projects, and analytics Achievements: Awarded for the most valuable contribution for four consecutive quarters of 2016 at Kraftiny

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Mumbai University in 2011

PG: M.Tech (Communications Engineering and IT) from Germany, Hochschule Darmstadt in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Scrum Master Prince2

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Jira, Confluence		2021	6 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Microsoft Sharepoint	Office 365	2021	8 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
MS OFFICE	Office 365	2021	9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Python	3.0	2021	4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
German	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Marathi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Gujarati	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.